Iqbal Shah

Software Engineer

→ +91-6398595433
➡ iqbalshah9368@gmail.com
♠ Iqbalshah0987
➡ iqbal-shah-215146229

SUMMARY

As a software engineer with 3 years of experience, I am dedicated to continuous learning and development. I work on designing scalable and efficient systems using technologies, like JavaScript, MERN, Python, and MySQL. Query optimization in MySQL and reduce size of pages and improve the application. I solve DSA problems on platforms like LeetCode and GeeksforGeeks to enhance my problem-solving skills.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Jan 2024 - Present

NishtyaInfotech Pvt. Ltd.

Single handedly manage a Job Portal (jobaaj.com) with lakhs of users, and managed a React.js-based platform (stories.jobaaj.com), developed an HRMS system, automated web scraping, and designed an Employee Management Portal, and created support management and blog portals and resolved MySQL queries to improve database performance

Full Stack Developer

July 2022 - Dec 2023

NishtyaInfotech Pvt. Ltd.

- Single-handedly created the Candidate Coordination Dashboard (CCD), to manage applicants and coordinate with companies for job placements, Developed optimized workshop program pages and payment gateways to manage payments, ensuring efficiency and smooth transactions for clients.

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, JavaScript, JQuery, ReactJs, NodeJs, ExpressJs, MongoDB, Relational Database(MySQL), PHP, Python, Java, REST API's, Git, Redis, Docker

EDUCATION

Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University

2022-24

Masters in Computer Applications (MCA)

Agra, Uttar Pradesh

Dr.B.R.Ambedkar University

2019-22

Bachelor of Computer Application (BCA)

Agra, Uttar Pradesh

PROJECTS

Job Portal (Jobaaj.com)

- Single-handedly managed the Job Portal jobaaj.com with lakhs of users, used technologies such as HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL, Python, and Node.js.
- Designed and implemented secure login systems for both jobseekers and recruiters, ensuring perfect user authentication and role-based access.
- Developed a **file compression system** using **Node.js** to optimize storage efficiency.
- Created **resume and JD parsing** systems with **Python** to data extraction.
- Optimized MySQL performance, improving portal speed, and integrated two separate databases for enhanced functionality.
- Integrated AWS S3 storage and applied CDN to reduce server load and improve content delivery efficiency.

Web Scraper using Python (Selenium)

- Developed a web scraper to extract job for the job portal using Selenium, BeautifulSoup, Pandas, and PyAutoGUI.
- Cleaned job descriptions by **removing unnecessary CSS** and **formatting** to ensure accurate **data extraction**.
- Scraped jobs from **company career pages** and **primarily LinkedIn**, daily scraping count range from **400 to 700** jobs.
- Bypassed IP blocking by enabling VPN using PyAutoGUI to ensure continuous scraping without interruptions.

Employee Management Portal

- Developed an **Employee Management System** to manage employee data, including **attendance** and **salary calculations**, using **HTML**, **CSS**, **jQuery**, **JavaScript**, **and Node.js**.
- Integrated **role-based access** control to ensure **secure access** to employee data and sensitive information.
- Implemented a fast CV uploading system, allowing the processing of large amounts of data in under a few seconds.
- Created a **document compression** system to **optimize storage** and **reduce file size**.
- Implemented a **real-time salary calculation** system that adjusts based on attendance, deductions, and overtime.
- Ensured **system scalability** by **optimizing the backend** to handle increasing data and user load efficiently.